<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="eb11-22-r-0935_01" type="entry"><p><label> RAYMUND OF TRIPOLI, </label>the most famous of the descendants of Raymund of Toulouse, was a great-grandson of his eldest son Bertrand: his mother was Hodierna, a daughter of Baldwin II., and through her he was closely connected with the kings of Jerusalem. He became count of Tripoli in 1152, on the assassination of his father. In 1164 he was captured by Nur-eddin, and was only released in 1172 after a captivity of eight years. In 1174 he claimed the regency on behalf of Baldwin IV. (at once a minor and a leper), in virtue of his close relationship; and the claim was acknowledged. After two years the regency seems to have passed to Reginald of Ch&amp;tillon; but Raymund, who had married the heiress of the county of Tiberias, continued to figure in the affairs of the kingdom. His great ability procured him enemies; for two years, 1180-1182, Baldwin IV. was induced by evil advisers to exclude him from his territories. But as Saladin grew more threatening, Raymund grew more indispensable; and in 1184 he became regent for Baldwin V., on condition that, if the king died before his majority, his successor should be determined by the great powers of the West. Raymund conducted the regency with skill, securing a truce from</p><p> by Sainte-Beuve {Nouveaux lundis , xi.) to have been composed chiefly by Clermont Tonnerre and Pierre V. Malouet, and it was regarded, even by moderate men, as ill-timed. The published Lettre de l’.abbê Raynal à VAssemblée nationale (loth Dec. 1790) was really the work of the comte de Guibert. During the Terror Raynal lived in retirement at Passy and at Montlhéry. On the establishment of the Directory in 1795 he became a member of the newly organized Institute of France. He died in the next year on the 6th of March at Chaillot. </p><p> A detailed bibliography of his works and of those falsely attributed to him will be found in Quérard’s La France littéraire , and the same author's Supercheries dévoilées. The biography by A. Jay, prefixed to Peuchet’s edition (Paris, 10 vols, 1820-1821) of the Histoire . . . des Indes , is of small value. To this edition Peuchet added two supplementary volumes on colonial development from 1785 to 1824. See also the anonymous Raynal démasqué (1791) ; Cherhal Montréal, Eloge ... de G. T. Raynal (an. IV.) ; a notice in the Moniteur (5 vendémiaire, an. V.); B. Lunet, Biographie de Vaôbê Raynal (Rodez, 1866); and J. Morley, Diderot (1891). </p></div>