<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="eb11-22-r-0898_01" type="entry"><p><label> RAOUL DE CAMBRAI, </label>the name of a French chanson dc icste. The existing romance is a 13th-century recension of a joem by a trouvère of Laon called Bertholais, who professed :o have witnessed the events he described. It presents, like :he other provincial geste of Garin le Loherain , a picture of the devastation caused by the private wars of the feudal chiefs. \ parallel narrative, obviously inspired by popular poetry, is ^reserved in the chronicle of Waulsort (ed. Achery, Spicilegium , i. p. 100 seq.), and probably corresponds with the earlier recension. Raoul de Cambrai, the posthumous son of Raoul Taillefer, :ount of Cambrai, by his wife Alais, sister of King Louis [d’Outre-Mer), whose father’s lands had been given to another, demanded the fief of Vermandois, which was the natural in-ieritance-of the four sons of Herbert, lord of Vermandois. On Ring Louis’s refusal, he proceeded to war. The chief hero on :he Vermandois side was Bernier, a grandson, of Count Herbert, vho had been the squire and firm adherent of Raoul, until he vas driven into opposition by the fate of his mother, burned .vith the nuns in the church of Origny. Bernier eventually &gt;lew the terrible Raoul in single fight, but in his turn was slain, ifter an apparent reconciliation, and the blood-feud descended o his sons. The date of these events is exactly ascertainable. Flodoard ( Annales , Anno 943) states that Count Herbert died n that year, and was buried by his sons at St Quentin, that .vhen they learnt that Raoul, son of Raoul de Gouy, was about o invade their father’s territory, they attacked him and put dm to death. The identity of other of the personages of the itory has also been fixed from historical sources. The second )art of the poem, of which Bernier is the hero, is of later date, ind bears the character of a roman d’aventures . </p><p> See Li Romans de Raoul de Cambrai et de Bernier , ed. E. le Glay [Paris, 1840); Raoul de Cambrai , ed. P. Meyer and A. Longnon [Soc. des anc. textes fr.  %  Paris, 1882); J. M. Ludlow, Popular Epics &gt;f the Middle Ages (London and Cambridge, 1865); H. Grôber, jrundriss d. roman . Phil. (ii. pp. 567 seq.). </p></div>