<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="EB_09-r-0001" type="entry">
   <p><label>RABÂN</label> (ראב״ן)—i.e., Rabbenu Eli'ezer B. Nathan of Mainz—was one of the most famous Halakliic teachers of the 12th century. He lived at Mainz and corresponded with Basin’s son-in-law, Rabbenu Meir b. Shemuel, and his three distinguished sons, Rashbam (q.v.), Ribam (R. Yishak b. Meir, who died young and left seven orphans), and Rabbenu Tham (R. Ya'akob). His great Halakhic work, צפנת פענח, or אבן העזר, is commonly called by the combinat ion of the author’s initials which heads this article, the Book of Rfibân, and was printed at Prague in 1610 fol.3 Other Halakhic literature by him is to be found in Kol Bo, § 123 (without place or date, but probably Naples, towards the end of the 15th century), and its reprints. More lies in MS. in libraries ; thus the Ehm Haro shah, of which no other copy is known, is preserved in the Cambridge University Library (Add., 498). R. Eli'ezer was also a fine liturgical poet, vying both in senti-ment and elegance with the poets of the Sepharadic school, as appears, for example, from the Ophan and other pieces designed for a Sabbath when there is a circumcision. Rabbenu Eli'ezer died in the 12th century. The date 5007 ( = 1247) which appears in the formulas of a bill of divorcement and a deed of manumission of a slave is most assuredly due to a scribe of the 13th century, who in transcribing Rabân’s book conformed the date to his own time—a practice often to be met with. Dr A. Jellinek of Vienna has published a History of the First Crusade (1קונטרס מרות תתנ״, Leipsic, 1854, 8vo)—a little book interesting in more than one way—which bears the name of Ràbàn. It cannot, however, be by the subject of this article, as one can see by comparing with his genuine work the questionable poetic stuff which forms part of the Konteres. The author is no doubt Râbân of Cologne. Nor does the commentary on אל אלהיט (for Pentecost eve) under the title of מאמר היטכל, which has been often printed, and of which the Cambridge Library has an old MS. (Add., 493, 1), The Hellenistic Rabboni (pa/?/30wa, John xx. 16) is the Aramaic ribboni used by a slave of his master, a son of his father, awife of her husband, a worshipper of his God. (Com-pare the similar variation of the vowel in pisho = 7rdo־xa.) Rabbenu signifies “our teacher” par excellence, and means in Palestine R. Yehudah Hannasi, and in Baby-Ionia Rab (i.e., Abba Arekha). Rabbah (רבה), also Rubbo and Rubboli, a title placed in the Palestinian Talmud and Midrashim after the names of certain teachers (T. Y., Berakhoth, i. 1; Kilayim, ix. 3, and elsewhere), corresponds to the Hebrew הגדול in the same connexion in the Babylonian Talmud (Berakhoth, 6a, and elsewhere), and does not, as has hitherto been supposed, mean “the great” but simply “the elder.” Thus many questionable Talmudic magnitudes disappear. (S. M. S.-S.) </p>
</div>